Anamika Adhikary

Regional Head, Emerging Businesses

Contact

Address

Bangalore, 560034

Phone

805 093 4832

E-mail

anamikaadhikary66@gmail.co m

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anamika-adhikary-59858

Skills

Project Management

Upper intermediate

Business Development

Upper intermediate

Customer rapport & negotiations

Upper intermediate

Strategic Business planning

Intermediate

Coaching and mentoring

Upper intermediate

Data Management

Intermediate

Software

Salesforce

Upper intermediate

Microsoft Office

Upper intermediate

Freshdesk

Self-motivated individual & an insightful manager with demonstrated knowledge of the Fin-tech Industry, best practices and operations. Hands on experience in directing and improving operations through effective employee motivational strategies and strong policy enforcement. Proven skills in enhancing productivity, efficiency and bottom-line profits with forward-thinking leadership. Bringing 6+ years of experience in field and ready to take on challenging, growth-oriented roles.

Work History

2022-10 -Current

Associate Director & Regional Head, Emerging Biz

Cashfree Payments, Bangalore

- Evaluating costs against expected market price points and set structures to achieve profit targets.
- Accomplished MoM volume growth of more than 30% in the new FY.
- Working on increasing the Net Revenue of the team with the help of multiple products & process optimization.
- Assessment of performance management structures and implementation of enhancements to improve frameworks and strengthen results of the team.
- Work closely with cross-functional teams to building various sales strategies, data and process improvement features.
- Documented processes and drafted SOPs to comply with regulations and company policies.
- Consistently serviced accounts to maintain active contacts and continuously promote profitable offerings.
- Established ambitious sales targets, managed deployment strategies and developed go-to-market plans to capitalize on every revenue opportunity.
- Managed team of more than 20 Account Managers, providing guidance, coaching and support.

2022-04 -2022-09

Senior Manager & Regional Head, Emerging Business

Cashfree Payments, Bangalore

- Built the farming side for the emerging business vertical that includes Marquee Accounts, Mid-Market accounts & startup businesses contributing to more than 500 Cr of monthly & 20,000 Cr of annual GMV.
- Manage two main regions for the organization- Bangalore & Bombay and working on growing the team rapidly.
 Currently handing a team of 15 members.
- Working on strategies and processes for the entire Emerging Business vertical along with the product & marketing teams (GTM, product penetration, market expansion, L&D, CRM's and tool management).

2020-09 -2022-03

Manager, SMB & Mid-Market Business

Cashfree Payments, Bangalore

- Built the SMB farming team at Cashfree from zero to 13 member within a span of 1 year and overlooked the entire growth of this vertical. Transitioning to head the Mid-Market Farming team currently.
- Expanded cross-functional organisational capacity by collaborating across departments on priorities, functions and common goals.
- Worked on building multiple processes and projects for

Looker
Intermediate
Quicksight by AWS
Intermediate

Languages

English

Advanced

Hindi

Advanced

Bangla

Advanced

- the overall development and growth of the organisation.
- Achieved 100% targets for all the quarters and made sure the team is focused on the same. Worked on reducing churn by 40%.
- Have hands on expertise in running marketing & product related campaigns for product launch and GTM activities for them. Worked along with the analytics team for various CRM implementations - Salesforce, Quicksight by AWS.
- Reduced process bottlenecks by training and coaching employees on practices, procedures and performance strategies.

2020-04 -2020-09

Associate Manager, SME

Razorpay, Bangalore

- Coordinate with all resources from Associates to Team Leads and map out project deliverables.
- Oversee training and on-boarding process for all newly hired employees within the SME team.
- Chair weekly meetings with executive leadership to identify opportunities for improvement, establish milestones and tailor products to individual markets.
- Working on metrics for product penetration and improving Client experience at Razorpay.
- Mentored and supported department employees to create strong workplace culture.

2019-09 -2020-04

Team Lead, SME

Razorpay, Bangalore

- Worked with team members to improve performance and implement training updates.
- Minimized resource and time losses by addressing employee or product related issue directly and implementing timely solutions.
- Prepared detailed team reports on updates to project specifications, progress, identified conflicts and team activities.
- Developed monthly and daily output plans to deliver on customer service and financial metrics.
- Developed strategies to retain High GMV clients and maintain long term relationships with them. (Schneider Electric, Save the Children, Goonj, The Ken, Rapido, Spencers, Chai Point to name a few)
- Worked on increasing the overall PPC for the team through various sales strategies.

2019-04 -2019-08

Senior Associate, SME

Razorpay, Bangalore

- Built and maintained relationships with new and existing clients while providing high level of sales expertise.
- Worked on Renewals and strategies for new product sale.
- Cultivated and strengthened relationships with new clients and educated clients on account services and capabilities.
- Collected confidential financial information from clients to construct comprehensive financial plans.
- Maintained constructive team environment through effective mediation of disputes between associates and application of motivational techniques.
- Oversaw project planning, schedule management and customer relations.

2018-04 - 2019-03	Customer Success Associate
	 Razorpay, Bangalore Developed highly empathetic client relationships and earned reputation for exceeding service standard goals. Worked on Churn management for the entire organisation and developed process to improve revival rates.
	 Improved sales abilities and product knowledge on continuous basis to provide optimal service and achieve targets. Liaised with customers and cross functional team to better understand customer needs and recommend

2017-06 -2018-03

Forensic Analyst

KPMG India, Bangalore

appropriate solutions.

- Worked on multiple engagements pertaining to Fraud and Misconduct investigation, anti-bribery and corruption issues as well as FCPA projects.
- Industries where I have conducted investigations are IT, Automobile, Real Estate, E-Commerce and Retail.
- Sifted and sorted through evidence and recorded findings.
- Developed team communications and information for client meetings.

Education

2014-06 - 2017-05	Bachelor of Commerce (Hons): Finance Christ University - Bangalore
2014-06 - 2015-01	Foundation Level: Company Accounts & Law Institute Of Company Secretaries Of India - NA
2012-03 - 2014-04	10th & 12th: Commerce Gulmohur High School - Jamshedpur, Jharkhand

Accomplishments

- Successfully built the CSM team at Razorpay from 1 to 14 members within a span of 2 years.
- Constantly overachieved individual as well as team targets by more than 15% per quarter.
- Build the SMB Farming team at Cashfree from ground zero and built Churn related processes to increase overall merchant count for the organization. Reduced controllable churn by 40% in a span of 1 year.
- Build the Farming team for Emerging Business at Cashfree Payments across 3 regions (Bangalore, Bombay, Delhi) and helped in growing overall productivity of the team.
- Been working on strategic product growth & GTM along with the Marketing & Product team.
- Actively involved in Cultural & CSR activities at both Razorpay & Cashfree.